GREGORY RUTHERFORD

Austin, TX 78723

Phone: 206-734-7555 | Email: gregorford@gmail.com

<u>Linkedin</u> | Github | Portfolio

SUMMARY

Full stack web developer leveraging a background in behavior analysis to build a more accessible and meaningful user experience on the web. Recently earned a certificate from the UT Austin Coding Bootcamp in which I developed a passion for front end development, specializing in React.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML, CSS, Javascript, Jquery, Node.js, Express, React.js, SQL/Sequelize, MongoDB/Mongoose, Github, Agile Methodology, Mocha/Chai

PROJECTS

Canine Connection | Github | https://canineconnection.herokuapp.com/

- A web app for finding lost dogs.
- My contribution to this project was setting up the server and backend framework, setting up the primary front end logic with react hooks, also form submission and client side form validation.
- MongoDB, React Hooks, Express (feathers), Node.js

Behavior Tracker | Github | https://behavior-tracker-gtr.herokuapp.com/

- A web app that track how many times you perform a behavior per week, as well as log the hours spent on each task.
- This was a small scale project that I used to better understand how to use react hooks, as I wanted to build a full MERN app from scratch by myself.
- MongoDB, React Hooks, Express (feathers), Node.is

Date Night | Github | https://ut-group7.github.io/Group7Project/

- A date planner that queries the ticketmaster and yelp APIs.
- My contribution included user authentication through firebase as well as writing queries for the APIs and assisting with front end logic.
- Firebase, Javascript, Jquery, Bootstrap

EDUCATION

UT Austin Center for Professional Education: Austin, TX — Certificate of Completion - Web Development

University of North Texas: Denton, TX — Bachelor's Degree (incomplete) - Applied Behavior Analysis

EXPERIENCE

Assistant Operations Director, Master Crew Leader, Mover Little Guys Movers	2013 – 2019 Austin/Denton, TX
Clerical Assistant	2012-2013
PFM Land	Decatur, TX
Sales Associate	2011-2012
University of North Texas	Denton, TX
Sales Associate	2007-2010
Half Price Books	Seattle, WA